Finding Aid for the Edward Gordon Craig Papers LSC.1006
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Section Seven: Photographs
  - Photographs of Designs for Productions
    - Acis and Galatea., 1902.; (4 items) (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Act 1. Scene 1., (No notation or coloring) (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Acis. Act 1. (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - The water god. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Much Ado About Nothing., 1903.; (3 items) (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - A dancer. (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Church scene. Act 3. (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Lighting ornaments., (3 sketches on 1 sheet) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - The Vikings., 1903.; (14 items) (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Design for Act 4. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Sigurd. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Egil. Servants. Act 2. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Dagnys. Act 1. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Kare's wife. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Ornulf. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Ornulf's son., (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Signurd's men. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Dagnys. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Weapons., (4 items) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Caesar and Cleopatra (George Bernard Shaw)., 1905-1906.; (1 item) (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Sphinx. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Hamlet., 1908-1911.; (5 items) (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Claudius. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - The Ghost. Mask. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Hamlet. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Ophelia's grave. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Hamlet. Playscene. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - The Beggar's Opera., 1924.; (1 item) (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Act 1. Photograph of original watercolor by Craig with his holograph notes on reverse. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of Gordon Craig's School for the Art of the Theatre
    - Interiors and workroom area. Florence., 1910-1914.; (17 items) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Exteriors and arena. Florence., 1910-1914.; (41 items) (Box 11, Folder 16-17)
  - Personal Photographs
    - Craig as Arthur de St. Valery in The Dead Heart, as presented at the Lyceum Theatre, London., 1889.; (10 × 9 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig standing. n.p., 1895.; (17.75 × 15 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig at window. Berlin., circa 1905.; (13 × 18 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig seated. n.p., 1907.; (18 × 12.5 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Inscribed, Ted. 1907. To Nell.
    - Photograph of Gordon Craig made in Rapallo by his son, Edward A. Craig, in 1919. Rapallo, Italy., (18 × 14 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig standing. n.p., 1939.; (11.5 × 7.75 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Inscribed, P. to Mix. 1939.
    - Craig in his library. Paris. Photo by d'Oray., 1941.; (12.5 × 7.75 cm., 2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig in his library. Paris. Photo by d'Oray., 1941.; (7 × 22 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig with child. Paris. Photo by d'Oray., 1941.; (28 × 19 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig seated. Italy. Inscribed, Patience off its monument. 1950. Photograph by David Lees., (14 × 10 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig in bed. Italy. Signed and dated by Craig. Photograph by David Lees., 1951.; (18 × 12.5 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig. Vence, France. Note by Craig on reverse., 1953.; (9 × 12 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig. Vence, France, 1955., (9 × 12.5 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Craig. Vence, France., 1955.; (9 × 12 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Note by Craig on reverse.
    - Unidentified house with wall. n.p., n.d.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm.) (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Section Eight: Designs
  - Original Drawings: Sketches and Watercolors
    - Early sketches., 1883-1898.; (11 items, Pen and ink; pencil; watercolor) (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Includes one drawing after Gordon Brown, illustrator of the Henry Irving edition of Shakespeare.
      Signed 'EW' [Edward Wardell]; E. Wardell; Ted; or unsigned.
    - Toy horse and rider., 1899.; (Pen and ink and wash, 25.5×20.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Preliminary design for Gordon Craig's Book of Penny Toys.
      Initialed in ink with holograph note on front
    - Toy horse., 1899.; (Pen and ink with watercolor, 25.5×19 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Macbeth., 1901.; (Pen and wash drawing of set design, 20.5×28 cm. drawing mounted on 28 × 36 cm. board) (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Conception for the sleep-walking scene.
      Signed and dated with holograph notes by Craig on sketch.
    - Gordon Harker as a watchman in Much Ado About Nothing., 1903.; (Pen and ink sketch, 32×20.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Signed and dated in ink with holograph notes.
    - Thiergarten, Berlin., September 7, 1904.; (Pen and ink and wash, 27.5×20.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Initialed, dated and titled in ink.
    - Houses at Dresden., 1905.; (Pen and ink wash, 27.5×20.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Siegelhausen near Heidelberg., June 1905.; (Pen and ink and wash, 28×20.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Electra., 1905.; OVERSIZE ITEM I; (Pen and wash drawing, 30×25.5 cm. Mounted in 48.5×40.5 cm. mat) (Box 28)
      Set design.
    - The smith., 1905.; (Pen and ink wash, 28×20.5 cm., titled in pencil) (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Inscribed in ink, Papa to Craig's son, Teddy.
    - Page from notebook with figures., circa 1905.; (Pen and ink sketches) (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Holograph notes in ink and pencil.
    - Isadora Duncan., circa 1906.; (Crayon sketch. 32.5×28 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Titled in pencil, I.D.
    - Another penny toy., 1906.; (Crayon sketch. 30×28 cm., titled and dated in crayon) (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - De kunst van het theater., 1906.; (Pen and ink, 25.5 × 20.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Facsimile of cover design for the Dutch translation of Craig's book, The Art of the Theatre.
      Inscribed in ink to Craig's son, Teddy, 1956. Holograph note in ink on sketch.
    - Set design with cubes and figures., 1908.; OVERSIZE ITEM J; (Pen and wash drawing, 15 × 51 cm. Mounted) (Box 28)
      Holograph note on back of mount: Drawing made of the first model of Scene in its first arrangement. The figures incorrectly placed.
    - A bold stroke for a wife-1718., 1922; (Pen and wash drawing, 18×24 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 14)
      Holograph notes on sketch. Design for a play by Mrs. Cantilever.
    - Claud Lovat Fraser., 1922.; (Watercolor, 30×26.75 cm. Matted) (Box 12, Folder 15)
      Initialed and dated in ink.
    - Unidentified design for stage scene., n.d.; (Pencil sketch, 12×11.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified figure., n.d.; (Pen and ink wash, 24×20 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 17)
      Initialed and note in ink, Something I suppose in igloo[?] but what?
    - Shylock. Act 3., n.d.; (Pencil drawing, 25.5×16.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 18)
      Identified in pencil.
      On reverse: Unidentified head (Pencil drawing. 25.5×16.5 cm.).
    - Lawrence Irving in Waterloo., n.d.; (Watercolor wash, 30×25.5 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 19)
      Initialed and identified in ink.
    - Outdoor scene., n.d.; (Pencil sketch, 6.5×10 cm.) (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - One-Dimensional Figures for Model Stages
    - Cut-out one-dimensional figures of cardboard for the model stage used in the Moscow Art Theatre production of Hamlet., 1909-1911.; OVERSIZE ITEM K; (23 items of varying size, colored with charcoal, crayon and watercolor) (Box 13, Folder 1-22, Box 28)
    - Cut-out one-dimensional figures of wood used for mock-up of the Moscow Art Theatre's production of Hamlet. Variants of original cardboard figures for the model stage listed above (folders 1-15)., 1909-1911.; (5 items, colored with paint and charcoal) (Box 13, Folder 23-27)
  - Original Prints: Black Figures, Black figures were inked prints taken from the one-dimensional figures listed in Box 13, folders 1 through 20. These prints were developed by Craig from the wood and cardboard silhouettes used in his model stage to illustrate the scenes he envisioned for the production of the Moscow Hamlet. The one-dimensional figures were inked in black and pressed on thin paper or cloth, revealing in the print the stylized features and folds of the carved garments of the original silhouettes.
    Newman. Annotations are to the left of the folder number. 23.x.86/jd; revised Lilace Hatayama, February 1987.
    - Untitled standing figure., 1907.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 2 of 16) (Box 14, Folder 1)
      50: JEWESS (S.4)
    - Untitled back view of standing female figure., 1907.; (34.5 × 25 cm., dated and Initialed in pencil, copy 15 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 2)
      58: IPHIGENIA
    - Untitled back view of standing female figure., 1907.; (Inked print on silk. 30 × 17 cm., dated and initialed in pencil, unnumbered) (Box 14, Folder 3)
      58: IPHIGENIA.
      Inscribed to Mama [Elena Meo Craig].
    - Untitled standing figure in profile., 1908.; (Inked print on silk. 35 × 15 cm., dated and initialed in pencil, unnumbered) (Box 14, Folder 4)
      68: GIRL WITH BALL (S.2).
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 27 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 9 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 5)
      80: THE PRIEST
    - Hunger., 1908.; (32.5 × 14 cm., dated and initialed in ink, copy 2 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 6)
      67: HUNGER
    - Hunger., 1908.; (35 × 27 cm., title and mounting notes in pencil. Unnumbered) (Box 14, Folder 7)
      67: HUNGER.
      Inscribed in pencil to Elena [Meo Craig].
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 27 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 14 of 35) (Box 14, Folder 8)
      72: HEWBA (S.2)
    - Fear., 1908; (35 × 24 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 18 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 9)
      84: FEAR (S.2).
      Note: lettering for FEAR is not reversed in cut, thus appears backwards in print
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 27 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 29 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 10)
      76: ROMAN ACTOR
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 27 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 17 of [30] (Box 14, Folder 11)
      74: ROMAN ACTOR
    - Untitled standing group., 1908.; (35 × 25.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 8 of 25) (Box 14, Folder 12)
      63: GROUP OF EIGHT MEN
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 27 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 5 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 13)
      69: SUSANNA
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 25 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 7 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 14)
      78A: ROMAN ACTOR
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 25 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 18 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 15)
      75: ELECTRA (S.2)
    - Untitled standing figure., 1908.; (35 × 24 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 30 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 16)
      70: FIRST ELDER
    - Untitled standing figure in profile., 1908.; (35 × 28 cm., copy 5 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 17)
      81: WORSHIPPER.
      Initialed and dated in pencil. State 2.
    - Untitled head in right profile., 1908.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 7 of 20) (Box 14, Folder 18)
      54: MASK
    - Untitled head in left profile., 1908.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 9 of 20) (Box 14, Folder 19)
      55: MASK
    - Untitled standing figure, back view., 1909.; (25.5 × 18 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 13 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 20)
      42: BASSANIO (S.3)
      44: LAWYER
    - Moses., 1909.; (35 × 27 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 14, Folder 21)
      64: MOSES
    - Lust., 1909; (35 × 29 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 4 of 4) (Box 14, Folder 22)
      65: LUST (S.1)
    - Hamlet and Daemon., 1909.; (35 × 25 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 6 of 40) (Box 14, Folder 23)
      8: HAMLET & DAEMON (Large) (S.1).
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, 1928.
    - Old Gobbo. Merchant of Venice., 1909.; (25.5 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 3 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 24)
      46: OLD GOBBO
    - Young Gobbo. Merchant of Venice., 1909.; (25.5 × 18 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 16 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 25)
      45: YOUNG GOBBO
    - Untitled standing female figure, back view., 1909.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 5 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 26)
      47: LADY-IN-WAITING
    - Untitled standing figure., 1910.; (20.5 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in ink, copy 30 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 27)
      40: SHYLOCK
    - Untitled standing figure., 1910.; (20.5 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 3 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 28)
      41: ANTONIO
    - Untitled standing figure. Moscow., 1910.; (25.5 × 15 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 17 of 25) (Box 14, Folder 29)
      73: OPHELIA [WITH WILLOW]
    - Untitled standing figure., 1910.; (25.5 × 15 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 7 of 15) (Box 14, Folder 30)
      57: GUILDENSTERN
    - Untitled figure., 1911.; (20.5 × 25.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 15 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 31)
      36: FENCER B (BLOCK 3, S.3).
      Block 3 - State 3.
    - Untitled standing figures in profile., 1911.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 3 of 15) (Box 14, Folder 32)
      48: THREE WITCHES
    - Untitled standing figure., 1910.; (35 × 23 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 4 of 15) (Box 14, Folder 33)
      56: ROSENCRANTZ
    - Untitled seated figure., 1912.; (10 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 14, Folder 34)
      14C: HAMLET SEATED (Small).
      Eighth proof of 30, 1919.
    - Untitled standing figure., 1912.; (31.5 × 23 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 4 of 7) (Box 14, Folder 35)
      11: LAERTES.
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.160.
    - Untitled standing figure., 1912.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 13 of 27) (Box 14, Folder 36)
      Hamlet, p.72.
      16: ACTOR (3/4 LENGTH. BLOCK ONE)
    - Untitled seated figure, back view., 1913.; (Initialed and dated in pencil, copy 5 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 37)
      17: POLONIUS.
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.24.
    - Untitled standing figure., 1913.; (25.5 × 18 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 1 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 38)
      Hamlet, p.170.
      13: ALORD (PREVIOUSLY GUILDENSTERN)
    - Untitled standing figure, back view., 1913.; (25.5 × 18 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 10 of 25) (Box 14, Folder 39)
      19: YORICK.
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.155.
    - Untitled standing figure in profile., 1913.; (21.5 × 13 cm., copy 3 of 6) (Box 14, Folder 40)
      STATE 2 USED IN Hamlet.
      18: OSRIC (S.1)
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.168.
      First state.
    - Untitled standing figure., 1913.; (20.5 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 2 Of 30) (Box 14, Folder 41)
      15: KING CLAUDIUS (S.2).
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.122.
    - Second gravedigger., 1913.; (27 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 2 of 25) (Box 14, Folder 42)
      82: SECOND GRAVEDIGGER.
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.149
    - Untitled standing female figure., 1913.; (30 × 27 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 12 of 16) (Box 14, Folder 43)
      38: BLACK GIRL (S.1).
      State 1.
    - Untitled standing figure in curtain., 1913.; (20.5 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 9 of 22) (Box 14, Folder 44)
      30: HAMLET WITH WATAIN: VIGNETTE.
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.21.
    - Untitled head in right profile., 1913.; (20.5 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 2 of 23) (Box 14, Folder 45)
      31B: HAMLET PROFILE: VIGNETTE (S.2)
    - Untitled standing figure., 1914.; (35 × 28 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 13 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 46)
      61B: BEAUTY (BLOCK TWO)
    - Untitled standing figure with crook., 1914.; (35 × 24 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 7 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 47)
      39: GIRL WITH STICK (S.6)
    - Cut in Untitled figures in scene., 1914.; (18 × 25 cm., copy 28 of 35) (Box 14, Folder 48)
      37: HAMLET & KING CLAUDIUS.
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.109.
    - Untitled standing figure with staff., 1914.; (25 × 18 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 16 of 25) (Box 14, Folder 49)
      51: CUCHULAIN
    - Untitled standing figure with pen., 1914.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 4 of 20) (Box 14, Folder 50)
      79: SCRIVENER
    - Untitled standing figure., 1914.; (25.5 × 18 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 3 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 51)
      12: QUEEN
    - Untitled standing female figure., 1913.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm., initialed and dated in ink) (Box 14, Folder 52)
      38: BLACK GIRL (S.3).
      With holograph note. Inscribed to Mama. Not numbered, not entered.
    - Player-king asleep in orchard. Hamlet., 1927.; (24 × 35 cm.) (Box 14, Folder 53)
      37JJ: POISONER 37KK: KING SLEEPING.
      As used in the Cranach Press Hamlet, p.99.
      Inscribed to Teddy. EGC in Vence, 1956.
    - Untitled mask., 1913.; (20.5 × 13 cm., initialed in pencil, copy 3 of 22) (Box 14, Folder 54)
      32: MASK FOR QUEEN
    - Untitled figure with stick., 1909.; (25.5 × 18 cm. State 2. Copy 15 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 55)
      43: LORENZO (S.2)
    - Untitled female figure with snake., 1915.; (25.5 × 20.5 cm. Printed on silk, not numbered) (Box 14, Folder 56)
      85: EVE (S.3)
    - Untitled puppet figure., 1915.; (28 × 20.5 cm., copy 4 of 35) (Box 14, Folder 57)
      86: KULTUR, CULTURE, CULTURA ETCIE
    - Untitled figure., 1908.; (35 × 20 cm., copy 6 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 58)
      77: ROMAN ACTOR
    - Untitled group of figures., 1907.; (35 × 27 cm., copy 5 of 25) (Box 14, Folder 59)
      53: GROUP OF FOUR MEN (S.3)
    - Untitled figure in profile., 1908.; (35 × 24 cm., copy 13 of 30) (Box 14, Folder 60)
      71: SECOND ELDER
    - Untitled group of figures., 1910.; (35 × 27 cm., copy 12 of 20) (Box 14, Folder 61)
      59: MOURNERS
  - Original Prints: Woodcuts and Etchings
    - [The Vagabonds]., 1898.; (Woodcut, 13 × 18 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Inscribed State 2. Copy 22 of 150.
    - [Henry Irving], circa 1898.; (Woodcut, 9 × 8 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ellen Terry as Ophelia., 1898.; (Woodcut, 24 × 18 cm. Signed and titled in pencil. Hand-colored and mounted on 35 × 25.5 cm. board) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Henry Irving as Louis XI., 1898.; (Woodcut, 17 × 10 cm. Signed and titled in pencil. Hand-colored and mounted on 35 × 25.5 cm. board) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Walt Whitman., 1898.; (Woodcut, 18 × 15 cm. Signed and titled in pencil. Mounted on 35 × 25.5 cm. board) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - The Windmill [or; Waiting for the Marchioness]., 1899.; (Woodcut, 18 × 11.5 cm. Signed and titled in pencil. Mounted on 35 × 25.5 cm. board) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Phoebus., 1899.; (Woodcut, 30 × 25.5 cm. Hand-colored and mounted) (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Variant of print used in Gordon Craig's Book of Penny Toys.
    - Scene from Dido and Aeneas., 1900.; (Woodcut, 13 × 16.5 cm. Signed and titled in pencil. Hand-colored and mounted on 35 × 25.5 cm. board) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - [Design for backcloth]., 1900.; (Woodcut, 13 × 18 cm. Signed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Inscribed in pencil, State 2 - Only 120 copies printed. Copy no.50.
    - Sorceress., 1900.; (Woodcut, 25.5 × 15 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Artist's proof.
    - Design for a backcloth of a scene for the opera, Acis and Galatea, by Handel., 1901.; (Woodcut, 6.5 × 12 cm. Signed and titled. Hand-colored and mounted on 14 × 25.5 board) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Movement number six for Scene, plate 9., 1907.; (Woodcut, 16.5 × 16 cm. Signed and titled in pencil. Mounted on 25.5 × 20.5 cm. board.) (Box 15, Folder 12)
      Inscribed to mother.
    - Untitled street scene., 1907.; (Etching, 10 × 8 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Untitled. Scene, plate 4., 1907.; (Etching, 18 × 12 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - [Office of The Mask, Florence]., 1907.; (Woodcut, 18 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 15)
      Inscribed, State 2. Copy 6 of 150.
    - [Scene]., 1908.; (Woodcut, 18 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - [View at Arcetri]., 1908.; (Woodcut, 11.5 × 16.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 17)
      Inscription: State 3. Copy 50 of 150.
    - [for King Lear]., 1908; (Woodcut, 18 × 10 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 18)
      Presentation to Craig's son, Edward A. Craig (Teddy) in 1919.
      Inscription: Copy 52 of 150.
    - [Stage scene for The Vikings]., 1908.; (Woodcut, 18 × 13 cm. Initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Inscription: State 2. Copy 89 of 150.
    - [Untitled mask]., November 1908.; (Woodcut, 18 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 31 of 50) (Box 15, Folder 20)
      Used as cover of The Mask.
      [Note: date of cut incorrect]
    - [In Tuscany]., 1909.; (Woodcut, 7 × 18 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - [Mask of a bookseller]., 1909.; (Woodcut, 15 × 13 cm., initialed and dated in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 22)
      Inscription: Copy 10 of 50.
    - [Untitled mask]., 1910.; (Woodcut, 23 × 15 cm., dated in pencil, copy 19 of 50) (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Mask for the blind man for Yeats' On Baile's Strand., 1911.; (Etching, 29 × 23 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 24)
      Etching inscribed to W.B. Yeats.
      Initialed and dated in cut.
    - [La Commedia]., 1911.; (Woodcut, 17 × 25 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 26 of 150) (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - [For the storm in King Lear]., 1920.; (Woodcut, 35 × 25.5 cm., copy 116 of 150) (Box 15, Folder 26)
      Inscription: To Teddy - Px-1929.
    - [Homage á Jacques Callot]., 1921.; (Woodcut, 12 × 17 cm., dated in pencil, copy 83 of 110) (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Villa in Ligure., 1924.; (Woodcut, 25.5 × 16.5 cm., initialed and dated and titled in pencil, copy 6 of 50) (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Santa Tecla., May 25, 1925.; (Woodcut, 16.5 × 21.5 cm., initialed, dated and titled in pencil. Mounted on 20.5 × 23 cm. sheet) (Box 15, Folder 29)
      Inscription: Printed 1951. 1 copy. Dry.
    - [Illustration for Robinson Crusoe]., 1927.; (Woodcut, 21 × 25.5 cm., initialed and dated in pencil, copy 24 of 100) (Box 15, Folder 30)
      Inscription: To Teddy from P.
    - [Illustration for Robinson Crusoe]., 1927.; (Woodcut, 5 × 10 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - [Man and ship]., circa 1927.; (Woodcut, 11.5 × 9 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - [Figure of boy]., 1927-1928.; (Woodcut, 25.5 × 20.5 cm., dated in pencil, copy 11 of 60) (Box 15, Folder 33)
      Inscription: To Teddy from P-1929.
    - San Martino., 1938.; (Woodcut, 13 × 18 cm., titled in pencil) (Box 15, Folder 34)
      Inscription: M from P - xxx-1938 - September 16. State 10.
  - Original Prints: Bookplates Designed and Printed by Gordon Craig
    - Edy. [for Edith Craig]., 1898.; (Woodcut, 7.5 × 6.5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Edy, her book. [for Edith Craig]., (Woodcut, 10 × 7.5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - GC. [for Gordon Craig]., (Woodcut, 3 × 2.5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - GC-1898. [for Gordon Craig]., (Woodcut, 13 × 9 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Ex-Libris TN. [for Miss Norman]., (Woodcut, 4.5 × 4 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - JD. [for John Drew]., 1899.; (Woodcut, 10 × 7.5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
      Signed in cut.
    - GE. [for Gabrielle Enthoven]., (Woodcut, 6.5 × 7.5 cm., 2 copies, one hand-colored) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Oliver Bath-1899. [for Gordon Craig]., (Woodcut, 6.5 × 5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - EC. [for Edith Craig]., (Woodcut, 7.5 × 5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - CL-1899. [Cissy Loftus]., (Woodcut, 6.5 × 5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - ET. [Ellen Terry]., (Woodcut, 4 × 5 cm.) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Winchelsea - Ex libris Ellen Terry., (Woodcut, 18 × 11.5 cm; another 6.5 × 5 cm., both hand-colored) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - C. [Christopher St. John]., 1900.; (Woodcut, 13 × 10 cm., colored) (Box 15, Folder 35)